onetonline.org 2011-06-15

# Privacy and Security Statement

This site is maintained on behalf of the Department of Labor, Employment and Training Administration. As such, it is committed to adhering to DOL's privacy and security policies. We are strongly committed to maintaining the privacy of your personal information and the security of the computer systems on which this site operates. With respect to the collection, use and disclosure of personal information, we make every effort to ensure compliance with applicable Federal law, including, but not limited to, the [Privacy Act of 1974](http://www.justice.gov/opcl/privstat.htm "http://www.justice.gov/opcl/privstat.htm") , the [Paperwork Reduction Act of 1995](http://www.cio.gov/documents/paperwork_reduction_act_1995.html "http://www.cio.gov/documents/paperwork_reduction_act_1995.html") , and the [Freedom of Information Act](http://www.justice.gov/oip/foia_updates/Vol_XVII_4/page2.htm "http://www.justice.gov/oip/foia_updates/Vol_XVII_4/page2.htm") . 

We do not collect personally-identifying information about you when you visit our site, unless you choose to provide such information to us. The information we receive depends upon what you do when visiting our site. 

####  If you visit our site to read or download information, we collect and store the following information: 

  * The Internet domain (for example, "xcompany.com" if you use a private Internet access account, or "yourschool.edu" if you connect from a university's domain) and IP address (an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the Web) from which you access our website;
  * The type of browser (e.g., Netscape, Internet Explorer) and operating system (Windows, Unix) used to access our site;
  * The date and time you access our site;
  * The pages you visit; and
  * If you visited the O*NET OnLine website by following a link from another website, the address of that website.

The above information is used by software programs on our Web site to create summary statistics which allow us to assess the number of visitors to the different sections of our site, identify what information is of most and least interest, determine technical design specifications, monitor system performance, and help us make our site more useful to visitors. 

####  If you identify yourself by sending an e-mail containing personal information: 

You also may decide to send us personally-identifying information, for example, your mailing address, in an electronic mail message requesting that information be mailed to you. Information collected in this manner is used solely for responding to requests for information or records. We may forward your e-mail to other Government employees who are better able to respond to you. 

####  If you link to other sites outside of O*NET OnLine (<http://www.onetonline.org/>): 

Our Web site has many links to other sites. When you follow a link to any of these sites, you are no longer on our site and are subject to the privacy policy of the new site. 

####  Cookie Use Notice 

We employ "cookies" to provide better service to our customers. We do not use cookies to collect any personally identifying information from users or to track user activities beyond our Web site. We do not maintain copies of cookies on our Web site after you leave our Web site. 

Cookies are small pieces of temporary data that are exchanged between a Web site and a user's computer which enable a "session," or "dialog," to be established between the two machines. With the session established, our Web site is able to tailor its responses (i.e., identify and provide you with the information you want) and help you traverse our Web pages in the most efficient and effective manner possible. The session is often broken when our server does not receive further requests from your computer or you simply exit your browser. 

We limit our use of cookies to "session cookies" — types of cookies that are temporarily stored in your computer's memory. Session cookies are normally deleted from a user's computer when the user logs off the computer or the user exits the browser. We do not issue "persistent cookies" — types of cookies that could be stored permanently on your workstation and reused each time you visit our Web site. 

####  Unauthorized Access Notice 

For security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, our Web site also employs software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage. 

Unauthorized attempts to upload information or change information on this service are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under the [Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986](http://www.usdoj.gov/criminal/cybercrime/1030_new.html "http://www.usdoj.gov/criminal/cybercrime/1030_new.html")  and the [National Information Infrastructure Protection Act of 1996](http://www.usdoj.gov/criminal/cybercrime/s982.htm "http://www.usdoj.gov/criminal/cybercrime/s982.htm") .
